Well, here's the same effect on the oscilloscope.
This is just the mode where the Tesla is working.
First of pulses.
And this is when we interrupt it, when there are discharges on the antenna.
There goes the interruption.
You can clearly see the sharp increase in amplitude compared to the normal ramping up mode.
And a very high operating frequency is being recorded.
That is, it turns out the antenna operates separately from the Tesla itself.
The ferrite in this case acts as a notch filter, separating the two systems.
You can hear their pops, and during these pops you can see the amplitude increase.
And the consumption doesn't change.
Actually, it's decreased, because it's coming through at low frequency.
Let's take a look now.
You can clearly see the increased ramping amplitude of the antenna itself.
I can't lock it in, but the effect is there.
The probe in this case is positioned like this near the antenna, in the air.